NGUYEN VAN TUAN

Hong Ha, Dan Phuong, Ha Noi • tuannguyen05119@gmail.com • 0977884443

Seasoned Fullstack Engineer with 10+ years of experience financial, telecommunications, and ERP projects while adhering to best programming practices and design patterns.

SKILLS

Soft skills: Collaborated with team members to enhance system operation and maintenance for improved performance.

Tech Stacks: Experience with Java, C#, Golang, NodeJS, Angular, ReactJs

Experience working with relational databases MySQL, OracleDB, SQL Server, Postgre SQL and noSQL MongoDB, Elasticsearch.

Experience in microservice architecture and Docker container technology

Experience with Message Queues: Redis, Rabbit MQ.

Effectively utilized source code management tools like Git and SVN for streamlined collaboration with team members.

Project Management: Apply the scrum workflow to achieve efficiency at work.

Mentor and guide junior developers, conducting code reviews and providing expertise.

Utilized troubleshooting and debugging skills to address coding issues effectively.

Extensive experience as a Full Stack Developer with a strong track record of successful projects.

Applied SOLID principles to write clean code, showcasing commitment to software development.

Engaged in bug fixing activities to ensure the smooth functioning of software applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Developer Sep 2022 - Present

KIENLONGBANK

Developed company projects using Java, .Net, OracleDB, and SQL Server, and ensuring software maintenance and upgrades.

Demonstrated strong problem-solving skills, quickly identifying and resolving critical production issues, reducing downtime by 30% and improving application stability.

Developer Oct 2020 - Sep 2022

MOBIFONE GLOBAL., JSC

Backend Developer

Enhanced the mSale-Pro system for phone number registration and management, maintaining and developing the system using Spring Boot, Elasticsearch, Rabbit MQ, Spring secure, and JWT with OracleDB.

Participated in brainstorming sessions and provided innovative solutions to technical challenges, leading to the adoption of new technologies and improved development workflows.

Implemented monitoring and logging solutions, leading to a 20% reduction in time taken to identify and resolve production issues.

Developer Jul 2017 - Oct 2021

Viettel Commerce Full Stack Developer

Contributed to the development and maintenance of company projects and join the company's outsourcing project. Utilized Java, Golang, NodeJS, Angular, ReactJs, OracleDB, MySQL for system maintenance and upgrades.

Resolved critical production incidents, maintaining a 99.9% service uptime and ensuring a seamless user experience.

Contributed to team knowledge sharing initiatives, conducting workshops on new tools and techniques, resulting in an upskilled and more efficient development team.

Participated in code reviews and provided valuable feedback, leading to a 30% reduction in bugs and enhanced code quality.

Engaged in sprint planning and retrospectives, helping the team achieve a consistent velocity and timely delivery of features.

Developer Aug 2013 - Jul 2017

SMARTBOOKS CO.,LTD

Software Development

 $Participated \ in \ software \ maintenance, \ upgrades, \ and \ bug \ fixing \ using \ C\#, \ Visual \ Foxpro, \ and \ SQL \ Server.$

Assisted in the migration of legacy code to newer frameworks, enhancing maintainability and codebase stability while minimizing technical debt.

Conducted performance profiling and optimizations, resulting in a 20% reduction in memory usage and improved application stability.

PROJECTS

KienlongBank's application and websites

Sep 2022 - Present

Development report for core banking, Portal website, Lotus application, Lucky application, Debt settlement website, Assets Management website.

Database: OracleDB, SQL Server.

Technologies used: Java, Oracle FLEXCUBE, .NET.

mSale, mSale-Pro Oct 2021 - Sep 2022

mSale-Pro is an upgraded version of mSale for performance and expandability. It is a system for registration and management of phone numbers. The system is used by store associates and tellers.

Database: OracleDB.

Technologies used: Spring boot, Elasticsearch, Rabbit MQ, Spring secure, JWT, IBM Java framework.

ViettelPost e-Wallet Feb 2021 - Oct 2021

Application for ViettelPost's delivery staff, warehouse staff, postmen for financial management and reconciliation. Link to bank accounts to deposit and withdraw money.

Database: TiDB.

Technologies used: Golang.

Competency management website, Voffice website

Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

Competency management website support management and lookup information, experience and capacity of employees.

VOFFICE is a document management system and electronic operation operating system.

Database: OracleDB, MySQL.

Technologies used: Java Springboot, Angular, Java Struts 2.

Chatbot Training Website, Website supports data management of image recognition

Nov 2019 - Aug 2020

Chatbot Training Website is supports data management and configuration for chatbots.

website that supports data management of image recognition.

Database: MySQL.

Technologies used: REACTJS, NODEJS.

Online sales application, Learning apps for elementary students

Aug 2018 - Nov 2019

Online sales application is a website and sales application. Use for merchants and collaborators.

Learning apps for elementary students is an application for students to do and review exercises close to the actual learning program.

Database: OracleDB.

Technologies used: JSP Servlet, JSPtaglib, NODEJS.

Online multiple choice exam system

Aug 2017 - Aug 2018

The website supports creating and managing online exams.

Database: OracleDB.

Technologies used: JSP Servlet.

Accounting software development

Aug 2013 - Aug 2017

Accounting software for investors, businesses, agencies and organizations.

Database: Visual FoxPro, SQL Server. Technologies used: Visual FoxPro, C#.

LANGUAGES

Vietnamese (Native proficiency) • English (Limited working proficiency)

EDUCATION

Engineer of Computer science
Hanoi University of Industry

Jul 2016 - Sep 2018

GPA: Good **Sep 2010 - Jul 2013**

Bachelor of Information Technology

GPA: Ordinary

University Of Transport Technology